A college-issued ID number is a good example of a primary key.
رقم معرّف إصدار جامعي هو مثال جيد على المفتاح الرئيسي.
It's a unique identifier that somebody has issued for just this purpose.
إنه معرف فريد أصدره شخص ما لهذا الغرض فقط.
As long as everyone in the course is an enrolled student,
طالما كان الجميع في الدورة في صورة طلاب مسجلين،
they will have a unique ID.
فسيحصلون على معرف فريد.
Home mailing address is not a valid primary key.
لا يعد عنوان المراسلات المنزلية مفتاحًا رئيسيًا صالحًا.
What would happen if you had two students taking the course who live in
ماذا سيحدث إذا كان لديك اثنين من الطلاب في الدورة يعيشان
the same house?
في نفس المنزل؟
Students' email address might be an okay primary key.
قد يكون عنوان البريد الإلكتروني للطلاب مفتاحًا رئيسيًا جيدًا.
College students don't share email addresses with each other,
لا يشارك طلاب الكلية عناوين البريد الإلكتروني مع بعضهم البعض،
so this is a correct choice.
لذلك فهذا اختيار صحيح.
But it isn't a great primary key though, because people sometimes change their
ولكنه ليس مفتاحًا رئيسيًا رائعًا، لأن الناس يغيّرون عناوين
email addresses and that can be annoying to work around in your application.
بريدهم الإلكتروني أحيانًا ويمكن أن يكون الأمر مزعجًا لتجنب تطبيقك.
Date of birth is not a valid primary key.
لا يعد تاريخ الميلاد مفتاحًا رئيسيًا صالحًا.
There's a famous math example called the birthday problem that proves that
هناك مثال رياضي شهير يسمى مشكلة عيد الميلاد التي تثبت
you only need 23 people in a room to have a 50/50 chance of two people in
أنك تحتاج فقط إلى 23 شخصًا في غرفة للحصول على فرصة 50/50 لشخصين
the room sharing a birthday.
في الغرفة يتشاركان في عيد الميلاد.
Also, college students are frequently around the same age, so
أيضًا، كثيرًا ما يكون طلاب الجامعات من نفس الفئة العمرية، لذلك
there's a good chance that two students will share the same date of birth.
هناك فرصة جيدة أن يتشارك طالبان في نفس تاريخ الميلاد.
In any event, a primary key shouldn't just be maybe unique.
على أي حال، لا ينبغي أن يكون المفتاح الرئيسي فريدًا فحسب.
It has to be definitely unique.
بل يجب أن يكون فريدًا بالتأكيد.
Finally, driver's license numbers are unique,
وأخيرًا، تكون أرقام رخصة القيادة فريدة من نوعها،
at least if you also include what state or country the driver's license is from.
على الأقل إذا قمت أيضًا بتضمين الولاية أو الدولة التي ينتمي إليها ترخيص القيادة.
The problem with this though, is that not everyone has a driver's license.
المشكلة في ذلك، أنه ليس كل شخص لديه رخصة قيادة.
Some people don't drive.
فالبعض لا يستطيعون القيادة.
And so, some students could have no value at all for
وبالتالي، قد لا يكون لدى بعض الطلاب أي قيمة على الإطلاق
this column and that would make it not a valid primary key
لهذا العمود، مما يجعله ليس مفتاحًا رئيسيًا صالحًا